www.linkedin.com/in/rickrejeleene

github.com/ludwigwittgenstein2

http://rickrejeleene.me/

401-430-0767

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

PhD Machine Learning candidate with extensive North America work experience across machine learning, software engineering, product operations and data science. Aptitude to tackle complex social and technical challenges based on thorough critical thinking skills with experience across a broad array of applications and industries. Understands and balances interdisciplinary need of technology with respect for the human aspect to arrive at competitive and social benefits. Works well across multiple functions and within the hierarchy. Trilingual, insatiable reader and described by peers as visionary, committed, caring and a good listener.

EDUCATION

University of Arkansas, Little Rock, USA

2019 - Current

- PhD in Machine Learning, ORISE Fellowship (Awarded to most talented researchers by Dept of Energy)
- Andrew Crittenden Mitchell, Marian Williams Scholarship (Awarded for outstanding academic abilities)

University of Oxford - Summer Semester, London, UK

2022

• Machine Learning Fundamentals, ML for Healthcare

University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI

2014 - 2017

- Master of Science: Computer Science
- Thesis: "Kodai: A Software Architecture, Implementation for Segmentation."

SRM University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

2009 - 2013

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

- Languages: Python, SQL, R, Unix Shell, CSS, HTML, C++, JavaScript, Java
- Tools: Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Git, Trello, Google Colab
- Frameworks/Libraries: Django, NumPy, TensorFlow, Keras, scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Oracle OBIE, jQuery, AngularJS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Federal Drug Administration – Jefferson, Arkansas, USA **Machine Learning Researcher**, National Center for Toxicological Research

2020 - Present

- Formulating Novel Machine Learning Algorithm to describe Creativity
- Developing Generative Models in Deep Learning (VAE, GAN, Seg2Sq Models)
- Implemented State of the Art Models in Document Object Detection
- Implemented Language Models (Transformers, BERT, GPT, YOLO, RCNN) for image classification dataset
- Executed Document Text Extraction (Cross-Document Object Detection) to image classification dataset
- Developing Ranking Documents (Information Retrieval) for classifying image dataset
- Presented State of the Art Machine Models from NLP Information Retrieval Models for classifying image dataset

COSMOS Lab -- University of Arkansas, Little Rock, AK Software Engineer. Youtube Tracker

2019 - 2020

- Software Engineer, Toutube Tracker
- Designed jQuery scripts for building a new UI interface
 Developed feature in javascript for admin panel, thus improving interface
- Introduced novel machine learning idea of moviebarcode for summarizing videos
- Implemented novel idea of mobiebarcode in Python into production ready code
- Researched Reinforcement Learning techniques for applying into moviebarcode in Python
- Managed codebase in Github for moviebarcode

1

Triblio, Reston, Virginia

2018 - 2019

Product Operations Manager

- · Managed advertisement portfolio of \$1.2 million USD
- Achieved advertisement budget growth to \$3.0 Million
- · Developed automation test scripts for UI interface and features using Jasmine, Selenium
- · Managed client issues between both customer success and engineering team
- · Troubleshooted bugs for customers in ad operation product

Cru, Orlando, Orlando, Florida

2017 - 2018

Data Scientist

- · Developed pre-processing processes for data gathering, visualization, and analysis of data
- Facilitated creation of a strategic vision for Data Science Team
- Applied R and Python to curate dataset issues to address business KPI
- Performed data gueries in Oracle OBE platform for data collection, cleaning of donation metrics
- Compiled and communicated technical data results to stakeholders

Ace Academy, Providence, Rhode Island Computing Teacher - Winter/Spring

2017

- Developed a 3-month programming curriculum for Rhode Island High-school, with Dr. Vic Faye Wolfe
- Conducted CSC 101 class for 11th and 12th for web programming
- Established a new Data science curriculum class tailored to 50 Rhode Island high-school students
- Coached 20 high-schoolers, which helped them to gain admission in Computer Science programs in Rhode Island.

PUBLICATIONS

Youtube Video Characterization using MoviebarCode (2021)

Recep Erol (1), Rick Rejeleene(1), Richard Young, Thomas Marcoux, Muhammad Nihal International Aerosol Research Assembly (IARA)

No-boundary thinking: a viable solution to ethical data-driven AI in precision medicine

Tayo Obafemi-Ajayi, Andy Perkins, Bindu Nanduri, Donald C. Wunsch II, James A. Foster & Joan Peckham (2020) Al and Ethics, Springer, Manuscript Reviewer

Kodai: A Software Architecture and Implementation for Segmentation (2017)

Rick Rejeleene, M.S Thesis, Software Engineering

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Bridges International – Affiliate Staff

2014 – Present

- Founding Member of Bridges International, University of Rhode Island, USA
- · Responsible for fundraising for Student Club
- Successfully raised funds over \$60,000
- Actively helped over 500 International students from 50+ countries to acclimatize with American culture
- Bibliophile, contributed summarizing over 490 books on Goodreads